<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Utah Data Scientist</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Utah Data Scientist</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Utah Data Scientist</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 22:21:42 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Doing data analytics at AdvancedMD</title>
      <link>/2019/06/05/data_sci_amd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 22:21:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/06/05/data_sci_amd/</guid>
      <description>The data team at AdvancedMD just had its first birthday a few months ago. Last year, the leadership decided it was time to invest in their data strategy by creating a data team with two analysts, a data scientist and a data engineer. Since then, they have revolutionized how data is accessed and used throughout the company. I spoke with Dallin Homer, the Business Analytics and Insights Manager over the data team, about how data science is done at AdvancedMD and any advice he had for those getting started in the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page/about/</guid>
      <description>About After going through starting my data science career in Utah and talking to people interested in getting into data science but not knowing how, I decided to put up this website to help.
This site isn&amp;rsquo;t about teaching you how to do data science &amp;ndash; there are plenty of those out there (Kaggle, YouTube, a million blogs). This site is different because you get to learn about what the workplaces are like here, what tools the teams use and the skills they value to help guide you on your quest into data science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/page/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page/contact/</guid>
      <description>Contact pelase</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started</title>
      <link>/resources/my-awesome-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2014 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/my-awesome-project/</guid>
      <description>(Under construction)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Job Resources</title>
      <link>/resources/job-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2014 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/job-resources/</guid>
      <description>(Under construction)
General advice Keep in mind as you do online research (including here) that there is no one ordained way to get in the field. There is a plethora of sources out there, and as you scour keep in mind this principle (borrowing from Tolstoy):
 &amp;ldquo;All [successfull approaches to getting into data science] are alike; each [unsuccessful approach to getting into data science] is [unsuccesful] in its own way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Python</title>
      <link>/resources/learning-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2014 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/learning-python/</guid>
      <description> (Under construction)
Setting up a project  A Boilerplate starter guide for your Python projects  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning R</title>
      <link>/resources/learning-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2014 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/learning-r/</guid>
      <description>(Under construction)
Getting Setup with R R is a statistical programming language. It&amp;rsquo;s open-source and used widely across different industries for finance, statistics, bioinformatics, natural language processing (NLP), making sharable apps called Shiny apps, and that&amp;rsquo;s just a few examples.
There are thousands of blogs and tutorials you could read, but we recommend starting by installing R and RStudio on your machine. Then you can follow along and practice and start developing code and apps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local happnins</title>
      <link>/resources/local-meetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2014 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/local-meetings/</guid>
      <description>(Under construction)
Utah Meetups Getting involved with the community is probably the best way to meet and learn from others, not to mention if you’re looking for opportunities to get into a Python field, you’ll have tons of networking opportunities.
Here are some recurring local events and meetups that you could check out (and if I’ve missed some please let me know):
 https://www.meetup.com/BigDataUtah/ https://www.meetup.com/Salt-Lake-Pyladies/ https://www.meetup.com/Salt-Lake-City-Data-Science/ https://www.meetup.com/SLCPython/ https://www.meetup.com/Analyze-Utah/ https://www.meetup.com/Data-Charrette/ https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Media</title>
      <link>/resources/social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2014 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/social-media/</guid>
      <description>(Under construction)
Newsletters  Data Science Weekly Newsletter Python Weekly Newsletter Data Elixir Newsletter  Twitter Twitter helped me so much in my early days. It was like being in a bunch of interesting conferences all at the same time and hearing what people were talking about in the community. I found some great tutorials that sparked my interest in programming and the rest is history.
Again, by no means is this list complete, but it&amp;rsquo;s a great starting point of people to follow to build up your feed</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/holdover/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/holdover/</guid>
      <description>Do you have any recommended resources?
For learning the basics of SQL we really like SQL zoo and Select * SQL
DUMP Setting up a Some web development was involved in creating an internal website where anyone in the company could access dashboards. If you&amp;rsquo;re stuck on where to start, try picking a problem that is interesting to you &amp;ndash; something you&amp;rsquo;d like to get to the bottom of or explore more with data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>/page/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page/resources/</guid>
      <description> Here are some handy resources!
Learning Programming Python Great Python resources here
R Great R resources here
Local events and Meetups some stuff here
Finding a job resources LinkedIn Stuff
Resume Stuff
Cover Letter </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>